Register of the John G. Veneman papers, 1959-1981
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1965-1977 (Boxes 12-15)
  - Excerpts from remarks, 78th Annual Meeting, County Supervisors Association of California, Palm Springs, California, 1972 November 15 (Box-folder 15: 21)
  - Speech, Dedication, Easter Seal Rehabilitation Center and Workshop, Riverside and Imperial Counties, California, 1972 November 18 (Box-folder 15: 22)
  - Partial text of remarks, National Conference, State Legislative Leaders Convention, Miami Beach, Florida, 1972 December 5 (Box-folder 15: 23)
  - Excerpts from remarks, State Legislators Conference, Bal Harbor, Florida, 1973 January 12 (Box-folder 15: 24)
  - Statement, Arthur J. Altmeyer Award Ceremony, 1973 January 19 (Box-folder 15: 25)
  - Briefing remarks for Frank Carlucci, Washington, D.C., 1973 January 22 (Box-folder 15: 26)
  - Partial text of remarks, Annual Meeting, United Services Community, San Diego, California, 1973 February 14 (Box-folder 15: 27)
  - Excerpts from remarks, Federation of American Hospitals, San Francisco, California, 1973 February 22 (Box-folder 15: 28)
  - Speech, The Conference Board, Public Affairs Outlook Conference, Waldorf Astoria, New York City, New York, 1975 March 18 (Box-folder 15: 29)
  - "The Innovative Capacity of State Legislatures to Deal with Health Problems," luncheon speech, Citizens Conference on State Legislatures, Key Bridge Marriott, 1975 May 23 (Box-folder 15: 30)
  - Remarks, International Conference on Women in Health, Pan American Health Organization, 1975 June 16 (Box-folder 15: 31)
  - Speech, 25th Annual Group Health Institute, Continental Plaza Hotel, Chicago, Illinois, 1975 June 24 (Box-folder 15: 32)
  - Remarks, State Legislator Conference-1975, Breakers Hotel, Palm Beach, Florida, 1975 July 22 (Box-folder 15: 33)
  - Keynote address, County Supervisors Association of California, Legislative Affairs Forum, 1976 January 22 (Box-folder 15: 34)
  - Speech, IBM Public Sector Conference, Stauffer's National Center, Alexandria, Virginia, 1976 February 9 (Box-folder 15: 35)
  - Remarks, 1976 Ripon National Issues Conference, Stauffer's National Center Inn, Arlington, Virginia, 1976 February 28 (Box-folder 15: 36)
  - Remarks, Conference on Health Maintenance Organizations, sponsored by the Greater Albuquerque Chamber of Commerce and the Chamber of Commerce of the United States, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1976 May 12 (Box-folder 15: 37)
  - Address, Stanislaus State College Commencement, Turlock, California, 1976 May 29 (Box-folder 15: 38)
  - Remarks, Conference on the Future Role of Business in America, St. Francis Hotel, San Francisco, California, 1977 May 1-3 (Box-folder 15: 39)
  - "What Led to the HMO Initiative and How It Was Developed," speech, Conference on Toward a National Health Policy, American Public Health Association, Washington Hilton, Washington, D.C., 1977 November 2 (Box-folder 15: 40)
- WHITE HOUSE FILE, 1969-1978 (Boxes 16-21)
  Clippings, comments, correspondence, cost assessment, curriculum vitae, fact sheets, memoranda, messages, minutes of meetings, notes, pamphlets, press conferences, press releases, printed matter, remarks, report, statements, telephone logs, and writings by others relating to the years John Veneman was associated with the White House. It also includes papers relating to the domestic policy agenda under President Gerald Ford and his State of the Union address.
  - General (Box-folder 16: 1)
  - Clippings (Box-folder 16: 2)
  - Comments (Box-folder 16: 3)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1978, undated
    - Undated (Box-folder 16: 4)
    - 1969-1971 (Box-folder 16: 5-7)
    - 1972-1973 (Box-folder 16: 8-11)
    - 1975 April-December (Box-folder 16: 12-21)
    - 1976 (Box-folder 17: 1-12)
    - 1977-1978 (Box-folder 17: 13-14)
  - Cost assessment (Box-folder 17: 15)
  - Curriculum vitae (Box-folder 17: 16)
  - Fact sheets (Box-folder 17: 17)
  - Memoranda, 1969-1977
    - 1969 (Box-folder 17: 18-19)
      Includes declassified records returned to file after February 2016 release by Hoover.
    - 1970 (Box-folder 17: 20)
    - 1971 (Box-folder 17: 21)
    - 1972 (Box-folder 18: 1)
    - 1973 (Box-folder 18: 2)
    - 1975 March-December (Box-folder 18: 3-12)
      Folders 5, 6, 8, 9, 11, and 12 include declassified records returned to file after February 2016 release by Hoover.
    - 1976 (Box-folder 19: 1-12)
      Folders 1, 2, 4, 5, 9, 10, and 12 include declassified records returned to file after February 2016 release by Hoover.
    - 1977 (Box-folder 19: 13)
  - Messages (Box-folder 19: 14)
  - Minutes of meetings, 1971-1976
    - 1971-1972 (Box-folder 19: 15)
    - 1975-1976 (Box-folder 19: 16)
  - Notes (Box-folder 19: 17)
  - Pamphlet (Box-folder 19: 18)
  - Press conferences (Box-folder 19: 19)
  - Press releases (Box-folder 19: 20)
  - Printed matter (Box-folder 19: 21)
  - Remarks (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Report (Box-folder 20: 2)
  - Statements (Box-folder 20: 3)
  - Subject file
    - Public forums on domestic policy
      - General (Box-folder 20: 4)
      - Clippings (Box-folder 20: 5)
      - Itinerary (Box-folder 20: 6)
      - Memoranda, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 20: 7-8)
      - Minutes of meetings, 1975 (Box-folder 20: 9)
      - Press releases (Box-folder 20: 10)
      - Printed matter (Box-folder 20: 11-13)
      - Remarks (Box-folder 20: 14)
      - Report (Box-folder 20: 15)
      - Schedule (Box-folder 20: 16)
      - Statement (Box-folder 20: 17)
      - Telegrams (Box-folder 20: 18)
      - Testimony (Box-folder 20: 19)
    - State of the Union
      - General (Box-folder 20: 20)
      - Memoranda (Box-folder 20: 21)
      - Message (Box-folder 20: 22)
      - Minutes of meetings (Box-folder 20: 23)
  - Telephone logs
    - Undated (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - 1975-1976 (Box-folder 21: 2-3)
  - Testimony (Box-folder 21: 4)
  - Writings by others (Box-folder 21: 5)
  - Miscellany (Box-folder 21: 6)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1965-1981 (Boxes 21-22)
  Assembly bills, clippings, correspondence, financial records, memoranda, minutes of meetings, newsletter, pamphlet, printed matter, proposal, remarks, reports, statements and miscellany, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - California - politics and government (Box-folder 21: 7-10)
  - California - politics and government (Box-folder 22: 1-11)
  - Urban Institute (Box-folder 22: 12-18)
- PRINTED MATTER, 1961-1972 (Boxes 22-26)
  Clippings relating to the appointment of Ralph M. Brown of Modesto, California as judge of a district appeals court in Fresno and the controversy surrounding the call of a special election to fill the vacant Assembly seat, the democratic candidate Charles Spencer who ran against John Veneman for Assembly from Stanislaus County, special election of 1962, speeches and activities of Assemblyman John Veneman, and his appointment and years of service as Under Secretary in the Department of Health, Education and Welfare.
  - 1961 (Box 22)
  - 1961 (Box 23)
  - 1962
  - 1964
  - 1969 (Box 24)
  - 1970-1971 (Box 25)
  - 1972 (Box 26)
- SOUND RECORDINGS, 1970-1972 (Cassette cabinet)
  22 sound cassettes of John Veneman's interviews on television and his speeches before various political, medical, and business groups on the issues of health care and welfare.
  - Group discussion, National Health Insurance, undated (Tape 1-2)
  - Unidentified, CBS Morning News, 1970 August 20 (Tape 3)
  - Unidentified, 1971 February 19 (Tape 4)
  - Remarks, Group Health Institute, John Veneman and reactor panel, Washington, D.C., 1971 June 3 (Tape 5)
  - Remarks, National Pharmaceutical Council, Shoreham Hotel, Washington, D.C., 1971 November 4 (Tape 6)
  - Press conference, American Nursing Home Association, Anaheim, California, 1971 November 5 (Tape 7)
  - Remarks, National Association of Manufacturers, Washington, D.C., 1971 November 11 (Tape 8-9)
  - Speech, National Municipal League, Atlanta, Georgia, 1971 November 16 (Tape 10-11)
  - Remarks, Council of State Governors, Washington, D.C., 1971 December 3 (Tape 12)
  - Interview, "Eyewitness," KABC-TV, Los Angeles, California, (taped December 14), 1971 December 19 (Tape 13)
  - Press conference and luncheon, Lutheran Hospital Society, Los Angeles Club, Los Angeles, California, 1971 December 15 (Tape 14-15)
  - Remarks, Board of Supervisors and Chamber of Commerce, Los Angeles, California, 1971 December 14 (Tape 16)
  - Interview, "Face the State," Little Rock, Arkansas, and press conference, San Francisco, California, 1972 February 11 (Tape 17-18)
  - Comments about Presidential Primaries, Minneapolis, 1972 March 15 (Tape 19)
  - Remarks, Town Hall of California, Los Angeles, California, 1972 May 23 (Tape 20)
  - Speech, National Council of State Welfare Administrators, 1972 September 15 (Tape 21)
  - Campaign speech, 1972 October 26 (Tape 22)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1971-1976, undated (Photo file)
  36 prints depicting John Veneman with William Coleman, Robert Dole, Gerald Ford, Marjorie Lynch, Bob Monagan, Rogers Morton, Ronald Reagan, John B. Rhinelander, Elliot Richardson, Nelson Rockefeller, Stuart Spencer, and Spencer Williams, and 1 print of Richard Nixon addressing the 1976 Republican National Convention.
  - 2 prints of John Veneman, undated (Envelope A)
  - 12 prints of Nelson Rockefeller, 1975-1976 (Envelope mB)
    Includes 2 depicting Rockefeller speaking before an audience; 1 print of Rockefeller with his wife; 3 prints of Rockefeller with John Veneman; 2 prints of Rockefeller with Robert Dole; and 1 print of Rockefeller with Elliot Richardson.
  - 7 prints of John Veneman, 1975-1976 (Folder mC)
    Includes 4 depicting Veneman with President Gerald Ford, Ronald Reagan, Spencer Williams, Bob Monagan, Rogers Morton; 1 print of Veneman with Mrs. Nelson Rockefeller; 1 print of Veneman with Stuart Spencer at a reception for Russian and American atheletes at the State Department; and 1 print of Veneman in a meeting with William Coleman, Marjorie Lynch, John B. Rhinelander and Nelson Rockefeller.
  - 1 print depicting Richard Nixon speaking at the Republican National Convention, 1976 (Envelope mD)
    Print is signed by Nixon, commending Veneman for his outstanding contribution to the success of the Convention.
  - 9 prints of John Veneman with other unidentified individuals and 1 print depicting him with another person, 1971, undated (Envelope E)
  - 5 prints of unidentified individuals, undated (Envelope mF)